<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on systematis.ch</title>
    <link>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on systematis.ch</description>
    <image>
      <title>systematis.ch</title>
      <url>https://www.systematis.ch/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.systematis.ch/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.133.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 23:00:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.systematis.ch/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Server Patching utilizing Ansible Vault</title>
      <link>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/homelab-patching-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 23:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/homelab-patching-ansible/</guid>
      <description>This quick guide shows how to use an Ansible playbook to patch a bunch of servers. This approach still is not fully automated, as it needs user input for the execution and provision of secrets from ansible-vault.
Prerequisites Ansible installed: Make sure Ansible is installed on the machine that will run the playbook. If you are on MacOS like me, just use brew install ansible. Vault setup: Install and configure Ansible Vault for handling sensitive data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Routing Traffic Through a VPN Container</title>
      <link>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/erx-vpn-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 23:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/erx-vpn-routing/</guid>
      <description>My IP was blocked from Growatt&amp;rsquo;s servers recently, because I started fetching my own data from them. This didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me, but anyways. I can&amp;rsquo;t change my public IP and it&amp;rsquo;s only rotated every once in a while. This meant I had to be creative.
In this post, we’ll walk through setting up a Proxmox Linux container (CT) to run WireGuard with a Mullvad configuration and then configuring an EdgeRouter X to force specific devices’ traffic through that VPN container.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Vault for Secure Credential Management!</title>
      <link>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/ansible-vault-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 22:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/ansible-vault-setup/</guid>
      <description>While writing the blog post about homelab server patching with Ansible, I figured there is a need for setup instructions of ansible-vault. So, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick guide on setting up and using Ansible Vault to secure sensitive data, like become passwords, for use in playbooks. Obviously, Ansible needs to be installed for this.
Step 1: Create a vault password file To streamline running the playbook without being prompted for a vault password every time:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor your homelab and get notified by Telegram!</title>
      <link>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/monitoring-kuma-tele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 23:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.systematis.ch/posts/monitoring-kuma-tele/</guid>
      <description>This is a detailed guide on setting up Uptime Kuma using Docker and configuring a Telegram bot to receive notifications when monitored URLs go down or have issues.
Setup time: 15 minutes (assuming prerequisites are met)
Uptime Kuma is an open-source monitoring tool for tracking uptime and receiving notifications when websites, APIs, or other services go offline. Paired with a Telegram bot, you can receive instant notifications on your phone or desktop.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
